翻译: Atropa
Rick 在这个宇宙飞船里
I got to tell you, Rick. It's pretty great
就我们两人 真是挺好的
To be in this spaceship, just the two of us, you know?
就到处这样游荡 这风格才对嘛
Just cruising around, Rick and Morty style.
校对: 晓小枫
我同意 Morty
I agree, Morty.
这样返璞归真挺好的
It's nice to get back to the basics
经过了过去紧张的 混乱的一年
After a pretty intense, mixed-bag of a year.
后期: Nico
- 哦  - 放松
- Ohh!  - Relax.
挡风玻璃就是干这个用的
That's what windshields are for.
我都不知道太空里还有虫子呢
I didn't know that there were bugs out in space.
压制: 怪查理
好吧 那你怎么想的 Morty
Well, w-what did you think, Morty?
生命难道是地球自己进化出来的
Life just developed on earth by itself?
我处理处理
Here, let me take care of this.
天呐 Rick 真恶心
Geez, Rick, that's disgusting.
我不想看
I don't want to look at that.
好像没有清洁液了
Yeah, guess I'm out of fluid.
让我找个地方停一下
L-let me find a place to stop.
嘿 你们星球有擦挡风玻璃的清洁液吗
Hey, muchacho, does your planet have wiper fluid yet,
还是说你们已经吓傻了要把我们当神拜了
Or are you gonna freak out and start worshipping us?
- 杂货店里应该有你要的东西  - 谢谢
- The general store ought to have what you need. - Thanks.
你肯定想要在日落前离开这里
Of course, you'll be wanting to be gone from here by sundown.
是啊 当然 等一下 什么 为什么啊
Yeah, sure thing. Wait a minute. What? Why?
日落以后节日就开始了
Sundown is when the festival begins.
节日
The festival?
哦哦哦 好吧 对于我们Millennia人来说
Ooh, well, for Millennia,
我们的社会已经完全没有犯罪和战争了
Our society has been free of crime and war,
- 我们生活在和平之中  - 哦 我知道这是什么了
- Living in perfect peace.  - Oh, I know what this is!
你们维持世界和平
You've been able to sustain world peace
靠的是每年有一天晚上 能到处
Because you have one night a year where you all run around
抢劫杀人 还不用承担任何后果
Robbing and murdering each other without consequence.
- 是这样的  - 什么
- That's right. - What?!
就像是<人类清除计划>那电影 Morty
It's like "The purge," Morty. That movie "The purge"?
噢 你以前来过这里么
Oh, have you been here before?
不不 但是我去过好几个星球都有这样的东西
No, no, but I've been to a few planets with the same gimmick.
你知道么 有时候这事也叫作"大净化"或者"红色时间"
You know, sometimes it's called "the cleansing" or "the red time".
有这么个世界就直接管这叫"杀人夜"
There was this one world that called it just murder night.
这 这是个搞大清除的星球
I-it's a purge planet.
他们一片和平 然后 他们搞清除
They're peaceful, and then, you know, they just purge.
这也太可怕了
T-that's horrible!
是啊
Yeah.
你想看看么
You want to check it out?
瑞克与莫蒂
电波诚译
第二季 第九集
所以 你在节日上一般都干什么啊
So, what do you do during the festival?
你是把自己锁在屋里 还是出去干点什么呀
You lock yourself in, or you go out and do some stuff?
哦 我干一些很坏很坏的事
Oh, I do some pretty bad stuff.
哦 我估计也是 老爷子
Oh, I bet you do, old timer.
天呐 Rick 快走吧 太阳快下山了
Gee— Rick, come on. The sun is setting.
我们得离开这里啊
W-we got to get out of here.
好的 好吧 这个玻璃清洗液多少钱
All right, well, w-what do I owe you for the wiper fluid?
免费的 哦 还有
It's on the house. Oh, and, uh,
你再拿点糖吧
Why— why don't you have some candy bars, as well?
噢 不会吧 你真好
Oh, no way. That's really nice of you.
我是个好人 至少现在是
I'm a nice guy... for now.
哦哦 这我不怀疑
Ohh, I don't doubt it.
- Rick  - 好啦好啦
- Rick!  - Yeah, yeah.
嘿 节日上好好玩呀 老爷子
Hey, have a good festival, old timer.
我也是这么打算的
I intend to.
Rick 快开门
Rick, unlock it!
就等一下 Morty
Just a second, Morty.
啊 快看那夕阳
Oh, look at that sunset.
别闹了
Stop screwing around.
好了 好多了 现在能看清楚了
There we go. Much better. Now we can see.
呵呵
Great.
嘿 Morty
Hey, you know what, Morty?
现在玻璃已经擦得锃光瓦亮了
Why don't we christen our squeaky-clean windshield here
我们正好看看大清楚怎么样
By watching a little of this purge through it?
什么 不 你有病么
What?! No! What is your problem?!
Morty 成熟点吧 你要是不想看
Morty, grow up. If you don't want to watch,
就别看 但是 你知道 这是我的车
Don't watch, but, you know, it's my car.
还有 你要是告诉你妈
Also, if you tell your mom about this,
- 我就把你给清除了  - 你太差劲了
- I'll purge you.  - You're the worst.
这个星球也是 你怎么会喜欢这种东西
And this planet is the worst. How can you be into this?
看这种互相残杀的戏码
You know, people are gonna kill each other.
怎么 你坐这儿就是想告诉我
So, what, y-y-you trying to sit here and tell me that
如果有个在线视频
I-if -- if there's a video online
内容是有人被砍头的那种
With someone getting decapitated,
- 难道你不会点进去看看  - 不
- You don't click on it?  - No!
为什么啊 为什么我要点进去看啊 你为什么要看啊
Why— why would I do that? You do that?
我不看 因为太无聊了
I don't, because it would bore me.
我吃早点的时候才看那种[哔]玩意儿 Morty
I see [bleep] like that for breakfast, Morty.
但是你不点进去看 我说就是因为
But if you don't do it, I say it's because
你惧怕你的原始冲动
You're afraid of your own primal instincts.
所以你极力压制他们然后
So you stuff them down and—
哦 哦 嘘 嘘 开始了
OH, OH! Shh. Shh. It's starting.
- 哦吼吼 开始啦  - 我不看
- Oh-ho-ho! Here we go.  - I'm not watching.
好 好 好 你的奖牌已经寄家去了
Yeah, yeah, yeah, your medal's in the mail.
- 我要离近点看  - 哦 好吧 随便
- I'm gonna get a closer look. - Oh, okay, sure.
等下就会有人扔石头
And then someone's gonna throw a rock
打中我们的车 然后车子坠毁
And hit the car and then we're gonna crash
然后我们就困在下面了
And we're gonna be stuck down there
剩下的就都是我们活该了
And it's gonna be what we deserve.
哇 这真是[哔]的互相残杀
Whoa, they are purging the [bleep] out of each other.
哦我的天呐
Oh, my god!
哦[哔]
Oh [bleep]
那真是 好吧 那真是恶心
That was— okay, yeah. T-that was gross.
看来我的胃还是没有我的眼睛坚强
Man, I think my eyes were bigger than my stomach
受不太了这个 Morty
On this one, Morty. Ugh.
我对杀戮的观赏欲一瞬间就已经满足了
My appetite for purge-spectating got filled pretty quick.
哦天呐
Oh, god.
离我远点
Get away from me!
不 不 救命
No! No! Help!
快来人救我呀 啊
Somebody help me! Aah!
好了 Morty 咱 咱们走吧
All right, Morty. L-let's get out of here.
等一下 等一下 我们得下去
Wait, wait, wait. Hold on. W-we have to go down there.
什么 为什么啊
What? Why?
那个可怜的女孩子 我们得救她
That poor girl. W-we have to save her.
唉 Morty 在宇宙里 有一种东西叫做
Uh, Morty, in space, we have something we call
不干涉原则 我们拿到了玻璃清洗液
The non-interference policy. We got the wiper fluid.
我们也看了他们互相残杀 我们要走了
We watched them kill each other. We're leaving.
帮我救那个女孩 要不我就告诉我妈你把我带这来了
Help me save that girl, or I'm telling mom you brought me here.
你这个小贱逼
You little turd.
求你了 放过我吧
Please! Leave me alone!
放过你 在大清除上
Leave you alone? During a purge?
我觉得不行啊 宝贝
I don't think so, baby.
没事的 我们不会伤害你的
It's okay. We're not gonna hurt you.
我叫Morty 这是我外公
My name is Morty. This is my grandpa.
- 我们是来旅游的  - 不再是了
- We're tourists.  - Not anymore.
哦天呐 这太[哔]爽了
Oh, my god. This is [bleep] awesome!
Morty 这太酷了
Morty, this is really cool.
嘿 你 你想帮我杀几个人不
Hey, y-you want to help me out here and kill some people?
很好玩的 而且绝对正当
It's fun. We're totally justified
因为我们是为了救一个小女孩啊
Because we're saving a little girl.
就是说 这些人我们可以随便杀 完全没问题
I mean, w-w-we're both free and clear to murder these people.
- 你没事吧  - 是的
- Are you okay?  - Yes.
我得找个地方躲一下
I have to find somewhere to hide.
好吧 你可以和我们一起啊 Rick
Well, you can hide with us. Rick?
- 怎么了  - 你觉得我们可以
- Yeah?  - Do you think we could take—
- 你 你叫什么名字  - Arthrisha
- W-what's your name?  - Arthrisha.
我们可以带Arthrisha上车么
Could we take Arthrisha up in the ship
然后 你懂的 就等着大清除结束
And, you know, just wait out the purge?
哦 Morty 我怎么能拒绝呢
Oh, Morty, how can I refuse
就你刚刚那么威胁过我之后
After all you've done to blackmail me?
你的交通工具 是神赐的么
Your vehicle— is it from the gods?
- 不  - 是
-No.  -Yes.
所以 大清除最开始的时候
So, uh, you know, when the purge started,
大家是一下就进入现在这种状态
Did people get into it right away,
还是 "等等 什么
Or were they like, "Wait, what?
这也能阻止犯罪么 到底什么原理啊" 那样的
This is gonna stop crime how, exactly?"
是啊 最开始人们花了不少时间接受这件事
Yeah, it took some time for people to accept it.
是啊 我猜也是
Yeah, I bet. I bet.
是啊有点像手机
Yeah, it's kind of like cellphones, you know?
一开始 大家都
At first, everyone was like,
"看那几个傻逼在那搞清除"
"Look at those douchebags purging,"
然后就变成了
And then the next thing you know,
"这真方便啊"
They're like, "It's just so convenient."
天呐 Morty你这是在为了喜剧俱乐部
Geez, you working on your tight five
准备单口相声么
For the comedy store, Morty?
你干什么呢
Whatcha doing?
看电视 玩手机吗
Watching some TV, playing on your phone?
- 你是认真在问我  - 就是想聊聊天
- Is that a real question? - Just making conversation.
是么 你说的哪句话让我能接着聊下去啊
Are you? What part of that gives me anything to work with?
我的选择要么是不作回答 要么冷嘲热讽
My choice is to say nothing, be sarcastic,
或者喊一句 "是啊" 就像个训练过的动物一样
Or bark "Yes" Like a trained animal.
这也不能算对话
It's not a conversation.
你这是语言绑架我啊
You're holding me verbally hostage.
好吧 混蛋 我去厨房了
Okay, ass-face. I'll go in the kitchen.
- 嘿 爸  - 嗯
- Hey, dad. - Yeah?
你干什么呢 进厨房吗
Whatcha doing? Going into the kitchen?
好吧
Okay.
- 是么 你喜欢这样  - 去你的
- Yeah, you like that?  - Screw you.
所以 大多数人清除的时候都戴面具么
So, uh, do most people wear masks when they purge?
我 我不想再回答任何关于清除的问题了
I-I don't want to answer any more purge questions.
好吧 没事的
All right, hey, hey, that's cool.
我没关系的
I can roll with that.
- 我的外婆  - 哈
- My nana! - Huh?
我外婆 我们得救她
My nana! We have to save her!
你刚想起来你外婆还在呢
You just now remembered your nana exists.
我 我受到了心理创伤
I-I was traumatized.
你大概经历过15次大清除了吧
Haven't you been through like 15 purges?
有些小时候就经历了
I mean, some as a child?
有人能帮我救救她吗
Will somebody just help me get her?
好吧 随便 Morty 留下
Fine, whatever. Morty, stay.
哦天呐 哦我靠 我靠
Oh, god. Oh, crap. Oh, crap!
- 滚出来 滚出来  - 嘿 喔 喔 喔
- Get out! Get out! - Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa!
[哔]滚出那个飞行机器
Get the [bleep] out of the flying machine!
哦我的天呐 好 好的 好的
Oh, my god! O-okay! Okay!
- 退后 混蛋  - 啊啊啊
- back up, asshole. - Ahh
- 退后  - 哦
- Back up.  - Ohh.
- [哔]退后点  - 啊
- Back the up!  - Aah!
如果这么说有用的话 我很抱歉
For what it's worth, I'm sorry,
但今晚说什么都没有用
But that's not really worth anything tonight, is it?
你 你不能把我们扔在这 你这是在谋杀我们
Y-you can't leave us here. You're killing us!
你听到了么 回来
You hear me? Come back.
你 你得回来 快改变你的主意
Y-you got to come back. Change your mind.
哦 天呐
Oh, geez.
Morty 啊 那个[哔]阿米什婊子射了我
Morty! Aah! The [bleep] Amish bitch shot me!
阿米什人 美国北美宗教社群 拒绝现代设施 过着简朴的生活
她想清除我 Morty
She tried to purge me, Morty.
你跟着自己的小弟弟走 现在我要死了
You let your wiener do the walking, and now I'm dead.
- Rick 她把车给抢了  - 你[哔]逗我呢 Morty
- Rick, she took the car!  - You [bleep] kidding me, Morty?!
她把我的枪和车都抢走了
She took my car and the gun.
我们现在跟这群混球没区别了
We're like the rest of these assholes now.
我 我们要被他们屠了
W- w- we're gonna get purged, Morty.
扶我起来
Help me up.
老天 要命了
Oh, geez, geez!
等等 Rick
Wait a minute, Rick.
为什么不用你的传送枪
Why don't we just use your portal gun?
在飞船里 蠢货
It's in the car, dip-ass.
疼死我了
Oh, god, it hurts.
她正好射中我的肝
She got me right in the goddamn liver, Morty.
这是银河系最辛勤工作的肝了
It's the hardest-working liver in the galaxy, Morty,
现在上面破了个洞 希望这血没白流
And now it has a hole in it. I hope it was worth it.
我只是想做对的事
I was just trying to do right.
那可不是今晚狂欢的主题
Yeah, well, that's not really the theme of tonight's party.
小心 一群强奸犯
Heads up. Rapists.
别傻站着了
Well, don't just stand there, Morty.
- 弄死他们  - 我上吗
- Purge 'em. - Me?
难不成我上 我拿肝上的窟窿套他们吗
No, me. Should I rub my liver hole on them?
捡根棍子什么的敲死他们
Pick up a stick or something and kill them.
呃 我们为和平而来
Um, w- we come in peace.
真是扶不上墙
Oh, my god.
那玩意我还多的是
There's more where that came from!
你们想被清除掉吗 放马过来
You want to get purged, you bring it!
把家伙放下 全都放下
Drop, drop your shit! Drop it all.
Morty 把他们的家伙抄了 赶紧
Morty, go get their shit. Hurry up.
刚才扔的玩意 我就剩一个了
I only had one of those things I threw.
现在拿的是一盒糖
I'm holding a box of tic tacs right now.
- 要吃饼干吗  - 不要吃
- Want some crackers? - No, thank you.
你什么时候能对我态度好起来
Are you ready to be nice to me?
为了区区一盒饼干吗
In exchange for crackers?
你到底怎么了
What happened to you?
赶紧找个工作吧 老爸
Dad, get a job.
你的生活太无聊了 才在这里找事
You're trying to create drama because you're bored.
有电话
Oh.
外公给我们的太空电话
It's the space phone grandpa gave us.
- 喂  - Summer 我是外公
- Hello? - Hey, Summer, it's grandpa.
你得帮我个忙
I need you to do me a favor.
- 我听不清楚  - 谁啊
- I can barely hear you. - Who is it?
我跟Morty在一个正在搞大清除的星球
Morty and I are on a planet that's purging.
- 你要记下  - 什么锡球
- I need you to take down... - A plan that's what?
我们在一个正在大清除的星球 大清除
We're on a planet that's purging, Summer. Purging.
我的飞船和枪都被抢走了 我们正在一场大清除中
We lost our car and my gun, and we're in a purge.
是Taddi Mason打来的吗
Ooh, is it Taddi Mason?
就像那部电影一样吗
Like the movie "The purge"?
是的 你得记
Yes, I- I need you to take...
那部电影烂透了
That movie sucked.
天呐 等一下
Oh, my god. Hold on.
不是Taddi Mason吗
It's not Taddi Mason?
老爸 Taddi Mason[哔]是谁
Dad, who the [bleep] is Taddi Mason?
- 一个朋友  - 啊
- My friend. - Aah!
你还好吗 我开免提了
Are you okay? I'm putting you on speaker.
- Taddi吗  - 是啊Jerry 我是Taddi
- Taddi? - Yes, Jerry, it's Taddi,
以前从来没人听说过的人
A person no one's ever heard of until now,
现在正拿太空电话打给你呢
Calling you on a space phone.
我分不出你是不是在讽刺
I can't tell if you're being sarcastic.
装弹 赶快
Reload, fast.
Summer 你得记下这串数字
Summer, w- we need you to take down this number.
- 别扯别的  - Morty吗 你没事吧
- Quit screwing around. - Morty? Are you all right?
- 当然有事  - 你怎么和Taddi Mason在一起
- No! - Why are you with Taddi Mason?
我[哔] 你[哔]闭嘴吧老爸
Holy [bleep] Dad! Shut the [bleep] up!
好吧看来 我就是全家人的出气筒
Okay. I guess I'm just this entire family's toilet paper.
你有在记吗 快把数字记下来
Are you writing this down? Will you please write this down?
- 好好  - 7 7 1 9 8
- Yes, yes. - 7, 7, 1, 9, 8...
3 6 4 2 1 1 2 5
3, 6, 4, 2, 1, 1, 2, 5.
你这狗日的
You son of a bitch!
Morty 我也不想求助
Morty, I don't want to be the "A little help" Guy,
不过你能搭把手吗
But a little help?
好了 我找到笔了 说
Okay, I have a pen. Go.
7 7 1 9 8 3 6 4 2 1 1 2 5
7, 7, 1, 9, 8, 3, 6, 4, 2, 1, 1, 2, 5.
就给我个勺子吗
A spoon, Morty?
- 你搞什么  - 对不起
- A spoon?! - I'm sorry.
你旁边这么多餐具
There's a pile of silverware next to you,
你给我个最没杀伤力的东西
And you throw me the one thing that can never kill anything?
我错了还不行吗
All right, okay!
车库里我工作台上有个架子
Summer, on the shelf above my workbench in the garage,
有一个带键盘的红盒子
There's a red box with a keypad on it.
你把盒子拿到外面
You're gonna take that box outside,
输入我刚才给你报的数字
and you're gonna type the number I just gave you into the keypad.
- 明白吗  - 明白
- Got it? - Got it.
恨自己的老爸是成长的一部分吗
Is it just part of growing up to hate your dad?
懒得搭理你
I'm ignoring you.
如果我能到那个灯塔顶上
Morty, if I can get to the top of that lighthouse,
就可以发射信标 你姐就能把东西送过来
I can send the beacon, and your sister can launch our package.
记住了 如果那里有人
Just remember, if there's people in there
而且他们想杀我们的话 我们先把他们弄死
And they try to purge us, we got to purge them first.
我们谁也不弄死 Rick 能不能别这样
We're not purging anyone, Rick, all right? W- will you stop it?
如果还想看见明天的太阳
Morty, if we're gonna survive tonight,
你得学会驾驭你压抑的愤怒
You're gonna need to harness your repressed rage.
我没有压抑的愤怒
I don't have any!
你这语气就挺压抑的
Spoken like a person with repressed rage.
我没有参加节日
I take no part in the festival.
如果你们想杀我 只求下手麻利点
If you desire to kill me, I only ask you do it quickly.
没这个打算
No such agenda, chief.
我们对大清除也没什么兴趣
We're not too keen on the purge, either, sir.
我们只想到你灯塔顶上
We were just hoping to get on the roof of your lighthouse
为我在地球的姐姐设一个信标
So we can send a beacon to my sister on earth.
- 那是另外一个星球  - 顺便说一句
- It's a different planet. - By the way,
别的星球也存在生命 不过重点不在这儿
Life on other planets exists. Don't let it distract you.
你们可以藏在我的灯塔里 设信标
I'll let you use my lighthouse for shelter and beacon-sending
不过条件是 你们得听听我写的故事剧本
On the condition that you listen to my tale.
- 好  - 成交
- Okay. - Deal.
我去楼顶把东西弄好
All right, I'm gonna go to the roof and set things up.
- Morty 你听他读  - 好
- Morty, you listen to his tale. - Okay.
"镜头淡入 外景 不知名的城市 白天"
"Fade in. Exterior. Unnamed city. Day."
"进步的路上 熙熙攘攘"
"The hustle and bustle is a symphony of progress."
"镜头略过形形色色的窗户 每扇中都是一个故事"
"We pan past windows, each of which contain a different story,"
"最终定格在Jacey Lakims身上"
"To find Jacey Lakims,"
"这个年方二八的惹火少妇丝毫没有意识到自己的美丽"
"28, hot, but doesn't know it."
"Jacey不得不停了下来"
"Jacey stops when her high heel gets caught"
"因为高跟鞋卡在了下水道格栅里"
"In the grating of a sewer."
"突然一个男人出现 用枪指着她"
"Suddenly, a man steps into frame and points a gun at her."
"她今天不走运"
"This is not her day."
"镜头淡入黑暗"
"Fade to black."
几个字浮现 "三周前"
Title--'three weeks earlier'.
你真的不想谈谈吗
You really don't want to talk to me about this.
老爸 外公和Morty情况危险
Dad, grandpa and Morty are in danger.
而你 正失业中 只是无聊
You're unemployed, and you're bored.
- 孰轻孰重自有分晓  - 别再说失业的事好吗
- They're a higher priority. - Stop saying I'm unemployed!
7 7 1 9 8 3 6 4 2 1 1 2 5
Okay, 7, 7, 1, 9, 8, 3, 6, 4, 2, 1, 1, 2, 5
怎么回事
Aah!
这什么东西 又闹哪出
Good lord! Now what?
听着 我是你的父亲 我只是想说 我是爱你的
Look, I'm your father, and I love you is all I'm saying.
- 仅此而已  - 说完你就满意了吧
- I'll leave it at that. - Fine, dad!
外公好像说过要先拿到外面去
Oh, he might have said to take it outside.
快点啊 Summer
Come on, Summer.
往盒子上输几个数字有什么难的
How hard is it to type some numbers into a box?
目标锁定
Target locked.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god.
我跟Summer这边都万事俱备
Well, I did my job. Summer did her job.
只欠Morty听完他的剧本了
Now all Morty has to do is finish listening to that tale.
Blaine说"可能我不需要新朋友"
Blaine: Maybe I don't need a new friend.
Jacey说"可能你是我唯一需要的朋友"
Jacey: Maybe you're the only friend I need.
Blaine说"需要还是想要"
Blaine: Need, or want?
Jacey说"我从未如此渴望过"
Jacey: I've never been much for wanting.
Blaine "这语气像是有迫切需求的人"
Blaine: Spoken like someone with needs."
- 老天爷  - 什么
- Oh, geez. - Hmm?
抱歉 请 请继续
Uh, sorry. K-keep going.
"Jacey伸手拂过他的脸颊"
"Jacey reaches out and touches his face."
"很明显他所需正是她所想"
"It's clear he needs what she wants."
"男女相遇 干柴烈火"
"She's a woman. He's a man."
"他将她揽入怀中 城市废墟在身后熊熊燃烧"
"The city burns in the background as he takes her in his arms."
"镜头淡出"
"Fade out."
几个字浮现 "剧终"
Title--'The End'.
"再加个问号"
"Question mark."
- 哇  - 可以吧
- Wow. - Yeah?
这真是 不错 写得好
It's...g-good job. Good job.
- 你喜欢吗  - 当然喜欢
- You liked it? - Of course I did.
酒吧那部分你没有笑
You didn't laugh at the scene in the bar.
那段挺搞笑的 但是我想听后面的部分
I...thought it was funny, but I wanted to hear the rest.
有什么想法吗 意见呢
Do you have any thoughts? Notes?
没有 仅仅是乐在其中
No. I-I just enjoyed it.
这就是我的意见 请再多写一点
That's my note, you know? Please write more.
- 感觉你在敷衍  - 不不
- Seems a little insincere. - What? No.
你不用好言哄我
You don't have to mollycoddle me.
我想改进我的写作 说出你的真实想法
I want to improve my writing. Tell me your real thoughts.
好吧 呃 从我个人角度来说
All right. Well, um, I'm not a huge fan, personally,
我不是很喜欢那个"三周前"开场戏的倒叙
Of the whole "Three weeks earlier" teaser thing.
我觉得
I feel like, you know,
应该从故事开始的地方下笔
We should start our stories where they begin.
不是从有趣的地方开
Not start them where they get interest--
- 滚出去  - 你说什么
- Get out. - Um, what?
我已经厌倦了 你砸我房门
No, I'm sick of this. You bang on my door,
向我乞求帮助 我和你分享我个人的一些东西
You beg me to help you, I share something personal with you,
你把它贬得狗屁不如
And you take a giant shit on it.
我们就问你能不能在这放个信标
Hey, man, we asked if we could put up a beacon--
不能 你们给我出去
Well, you can't. I want you out of here.
你这个没有安全感 小肚鸡肠的无赖
You're a petty person, and you're insecure,
你还发泄到我头上 明明就是个好剧本
And you're taking it out on me. That's a good script.
什么鬼东西
What the hell?!
我不管 你要求你们离开
I don't care. I want you out.
- 你说什么  - 把那玩意拆下来
- What? - Take that thing down.
你外孙是个小瘪三 快离开
Your grandson is a shitty person. Leave now.
- 你怎么搞的  - 我什么都没做
- Morty! - Rick, I didn't do anything.
我熬着听完了他的整个剧本
I sat through his entire screenplay--
你"熬着"听完的吗
You "sat through it"?
废话 难不成你还想让我留下幸福的泪水
Yes! Did you want me to weep with joy?
- 写得狗屎一样  - 注意言行 Morty 我们是客人
- It's terrible! - Whoa! Morty! We're guests here.
我已经努力做到有礼貌了 这都是他逼的
I tried to be a good guest! He dragged it out of me!
- 我这就把信标拆了  - 不行 这不公平
- I'm taking down this beacon. - No, stop! That's not fair!
你讨厌自己的作品
Just because you hate your own writing
并不说明我是个坏人
Doesn't make me a bad person!
满意了吧 你想让我切到三周之前
You like that? You want me to cut to three weeks earlier
你还活着的时候吗
When you were alive?
Morty 你把他清除了
Whoa, Morty. You just purged.
信标即将到达
Beacon arriving.
该出动了
Okay, time to go.
这下好了
Well, terrific.
老爸 怎么回事 你这是搞什么
Dad, what's going on? What's the deal here?
我只想陪陪女儿而已
I just wanted to spend some time with my daughter.
你长大得太快了
You're growing up so fast.
- 过去你就是我的小甜妞  - 是啊
- You used to be my little girl. - Yeah.
你还记得过去我们经常去操场玩
Remember when we used to go to the playground,
我推你荡秋千的事吗
And I'd push you on the swings?
当然 你总是能推得让我比其他的孩子高
Oh, you could push me higher than all the other kids.
那时候你小小的 很可爱
You were so small and cute.
我还以为你会被甩飞到街上去
I thought you were gonna fly right off into the street.
我还会吓到尿裤子
I used to pee my pants.
可不是嘛 我家闺女长大了
I know, and now look at you!
有份能挣到钱的好工作
You have a job. You're making really good money.
也不用付房租
You're not paying any rent,
所以你就有大把可支配收入
So you have plenty of disposable income.
天啊 爸 别这样
Oh, god, dad. Please, don't.
我只需要几百块
I just need a few hundred dollars
来熬过这月而已 很快我就有面试了
To get through the month. I have some interviews coming up.
我能预感到事情肯定很快就会有转机了
Something's gonna come through. I can feel it.
我要进去了
I'm going inside.
Jerry 看来这就是人生低谷的感受
I guess this is what rock bottom feels like, Jerry.
没事 Morty 今天是大清除
It's okay, Morty. It's the Purge, you know?
把守灯塔的老人推下楼梯这种事完全没问题
Pushing old lighthouse keepers down the stairs is totally cool.
Rick 这样很有问题 我不是那些人
It's not cool, Rick. I-I'm not like these people.
我不能在某一天到处砍人
I can't run around chopping people's heads off
然后剩下的日子还能安心地抱头大睡
One day a year and then sleep well the rest of the time.
你最好快点习惯 小傻逼
Well, you better start getting used to it, little bitch,
因为[哔]有人找上门了
Because we got some [bleep] company.
看 他来了
Hey, there he is.
我来了
Here I am.
Morty
Morty.
清除时候到
Time to purge.
tony! toni! tone!- <Feels Good>
老天 Morty 你还真开始熟路了
Geez. Wow, Morty. Now you're getting into it.
真想不到啊
Never expected that out of you.
好了 去找回我的飞船
All right, uh, let's go find my ship.
Morty 飞船就在那
Hey, hey, Morty, Morty. There it is down there -- my ship.
看起来好像 Morty
It looks to me like the... Morty?
舔我的[哔] 尝尝这招
Suck my [bleep].Eat this.
小子 你真的
Ooh, boy, you're really, uh...
你真是大开杀戒啊
You're really going for it over there, huh?
我觉得
I, uh I think, uh
我觉得那些人 只是想躲着
I think those people were just hiding.
我[哔]才不管
I don't give a [bleep]
够了 Morty 你在射一群尸体
Okay, Morty, now you're just shooting corpses.
- 喜欢这招不  - 够了 伙计
- How do you like this? - Okay, buddy.
好了伙计 够了
All right. That's good. Good job.
是时候回家了
Time to go home.
等等 住手 求你们别杀我
Wait, stop! Please, don't kill me!
我没想过伤害你们的 我发誓
I-I never intended to harm you, I swear.
我只想结束这个节日
I am trying to end the festival.
- 什么意思  - 我想利用这艘飞船
- w-what do you mean? - I was going to use your ship
去干掉那帮掌控这个社会的混蛋
To destroy the rich assholes that run our society
拯救我们这些被这个节日折磨的老百姓
And save my people from the horrors of this yearly festival.
[哔]她的 Rick 杀了她 杀了她 杀了她
[bleep] that, Rick! We got to kill her! Kill her! Kill her!
天啊 Morty 清除掉一点杀气
Whoa! Geez, Morty, purge it down a little.
"清除 别清除 "
"Purge! Don't purge!"
Rick 我不懂你想表达什么
You're sending me mixed messages, Rick.
Morty 你表现得
Morty you're acting like
完全像个神经病
A freaking lunatic.
- 冷静点  - 去你的 Rick
- calm down. - screw you, Rick!
我还要杀了你这只老弱鸡Rick
I'll purge you, too, you old, rickety piece of crap!
想了很久了
This has been a long time coming!
我要[哔]把你的内脏挖出来
I'm gonna rip your [bleep] guts out
涂在你那张傻逼脸上
And smear them all over your face!
我才不会
I ain't taking no sh--
抱歉让你见笑了
Okay, s-sorry about that.
那帮有钱人在哪
Now, where are these rich people?
门德尔松 E小调小提琴协奏曲 Op.64
敬又一年成功举办的节日
To another successful year of the festival,
让穷人们自相残杀几千年
Pitting poor people against each other for thousands of years.
等等 这音乐从哪里来的
Wait, w-where is that music coming from?
你什么意思
What is the meaning of this?
事情是这样的 我不想评价你们的做法
Here's the deal. I'm not here to judge.
我只是个从别的星球来的普通人
I'm just a guy from another planet.
但是这女孩是你们穷人中的一员
But this girl is one of your poor people,
我猜你们很心安理得地
And I guess you guys felt like it was okay
让她处在毫不人道的环境中
To subject her to inhuman conditions
因为这样永远没有机会能伤害到你们
Because there was no chance of it ever hurting you.
这在社会政治层面上
It's sort of the socio-political equivalent
就好比有一身武装盔甲
Of, say, a suit of power armor around you.
但现在情况算是扯平了 那么 Arthrisha
But now things are evened out, so, Arthrisha?
节日快乐 [哔]烂人们
Happy festival [bleep] suckers!
尝尝老娘的[哔]吧
Suck my [bleep]! Chew my balls!
吸我的超大[哔]
Suck my huge [bleep].
Rick 你想来掺一脚吗
You want to get in on this, Rick?
说真的  我已经够了
No, I really -- honestly, I-I've had my fill.
现在再杀就是毫无理由了
It's gratuitous at this point.
你真的不想来吗
You sure you don't want to join in?
感觉非常棒
This is really amazing.
但是 还是好吧 [哔]它的
Yeah, but --Ah, all right.[bleep] it.
有意见么 贱人们
Yeah, bitch,what's up?
现在让我们热舞起来吧
Okay, now it's time we do a little dancing
随着tony! toni! tone!的歌跳舞
To -- To Tony! toni! tone!
快看我的[哔]脚步 [哔]们
Look at my [bleep] feet, mother[bleep]
Arthrisha 露一手
Arthrisha, what do you got?
看我的厉害
Check this out.
不知这是什么歌 但我就[哔]喜欢
I don't know what song that is, but I [bleep] love it!
"Feels good"
"Feels good."
一首[哔]热单
It's a [bleep] hit song.
可能还是一首冠单
Topped the charts, I think. HO, HO!
*感觉很好*
*Oh, it feels good.*
非常感谢你的帮助 Rick
Hey, thanks for helping me, Rick.
你是个好人
You're a pretty great guy.
[哔]你射爆我的肝
Yeah, yeah, yeah. [bleep] you for shooting my liver.
有机会再见
I'll see you around.
天啊 发生了什么事
Oh, man. What -- what happened?
别担心 Morty
Don't worry about it, Morty.
听好了 如果你想打一炮的话
Listen, if you wanted to try to get a piece,
行动起来 最后的机会了
You better hurry up. Now's your last chance.
Arthrisha 可能我
Hey, hey, Arthrisha, um, maybe I could --
我有男朋友了
Uh, I have a boyfriend.
- 好吧  - 我不是想冒犯你
- Okay. - I'm not trying to be rude.
我只是不想你误会
I just -- I don't want to lead you on.
我懂的
I-I-I understand.
我非常感谢你帮忙终结了这个节日
I mean, thank you so much for helping end the festival,
但我已经有男朋友了 他只是
But I have a boyfriend, and, uh, he's just --
好了 你不用再说下去了
Okay, okay, you can stop saying it.
你第一次说的时候我就懂了
I took it okay the first time,
你不用再说了
And now you're just repeating stuff.
- 很抱歉  - 没事
- oh, I'm sorry. - it's okay.
你很好人 但我不能
Oh, you're so sweet, I just -- oh, but I can't.
你还在说
Yeah, you're still doing it.
从头开始建设一个社会不容易
It won't be easy creating a new society from the ground up.
简单有效的原则 想要什么就去弄什么
Well, a helpful rule might be if you need something, you get it.
- 很简单 对吧  - 我需要食物
- pretty simple, right? - I need food.
- 谁有给这家伙的食物  - 我有 但那是我的
- who's got food for that guy? - I do, but this is for me.
你不能多做点食物吗
Can't you make some more?
当然可以 我为所有人做食物的时候
Oh, sure. And while I'm making food for everyone,
谁来照顾我的孩子呢
Who takes care of my kids?
我来帮你照顾孩子 前提是我要有额外的食物
I'll take care of your kids, if I get some extra food for it.
额外的食物
Extra food?
人人所得一样的话 我可不会花额外的功夫
Well, I'm not gonna do extra work if we all get the same.
好吧 公平至上
All right, okay, fair is fair.
多劳者多得
If you do extra work, you get extra food.
那谁来记下
Who's gonna keep track
每个人"劳"多少"得"多少呢
Of who gets how much food for how much work?
你好 我可以
Hello. I can do that.
我来记录每个人应得的食物
I'll keep track of everyone's food,
用来换取食物
You know, in exchange for food.
那根本不是真正的工作
That's not a real job!
难道做食物就是吗
Oh, and making food is?
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch!
尝尝这招
Eat this!
好了 伙计们
Guys, guys, guys, guys, whoa, whoa.
淡定点 别激动
Cool it, now. Take it easy.
别这么好战
There's too much aggression here.
要不我们制定一段时间
What if we designate a period of time
尽情释放我们
During which we can all get this hate, murder,
内心的憎恨 杀欲和愤怒
And rage out of our system --
我很惭愧
I can't help but feel ashamed
我今天居然干了这种事 Rick
About what I did back there, Rick.
你是对的 我的内心太压抑了
I guess you were right. I've got a lot of repressed stuff
- 我需要好好处理 - 别担心 Morty
- I need to deal with. - Don't worry about it, Morty.
还记得那些糖吗
Remember those candy bars earlier
- 我们刚来的时候拿的那些  - 怎么了
- that we got in the first act? - yeah, what about them?
原来它们含有一种化学成分叫"清除醇"
Turns out they have a chemical in them called purgenol
这种物质会加重你的暴力倾向
That amplifies all your violent tendencies.
天啊 真是感谢天感谢地
Oh, boy. Whew! Thank goodness for that, huh?
松了一口气
That's a relief.
没错 冷汗都不用冒一滴
Yep. Don't even sweat.
你还是那个Morty
You're still the same old Morty.
你的人格没有受到损害
Your character's totally protected.
(现在不含清除醇)
Jerry 什么是"Taddi Mason llc"
Jerry, what is "Taddi Mason llc,"
还有为什么电话费要七百块
And why is our phone bill $700?
你很无聊吗
Uh... hey, are you bored...
你孤单吗 只想找个朋友
Uh... ...lonely, just looking for a friend?
打给我吧 Taddi Mason
Uh... call me, taddi mason.
每分钟1.99元而已
It's only $1.99 a minute to talk.
今天注册
Uh... sign up today,
我还会定期打给你
And I'll even call you on a regular basis...
也是每分钟1.99元
Uh... ...for just $1.99 a minute.
划算极了 我是一个好朋友
That's a steal because I'm a great pal.
我们可以谈体育 谈烧烤
Uh... we could talk about sports or barbecue.
Jerry 快找份工作
Jerry, get a job.
电波字幕组 欢迎您的加入
官方网站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@电波字幕组